# Alexa Rockwell

a.rckwll@gmail.com • (914) 325-4838 • alexarockwell.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Computer Science graduate with 3 years of industry experience as a software engineer. Seeking to build my knowledge of applied machine learning and artificial intelligence. Along the way, championing inclusive communities and recognizing opportunities to create impactful technology.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Graduate Coursework in Artificial Intelligence, Stanford University

September 2019 - Present

• Artificial Intelligence: Principles and Techniques, Introduction to Robotics, Mathematical Foundations of Computing

### Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Stony Brook University

May 2018

• Computer Science Program at SBU, Dean's List, President of the Stony Brook Computing Society, Vice President of Women in Science and Engineering Leadership Committee

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Software Engineer, Apple

January 2019 - Present

- Built graph technologies that support user-level photo features as a member of the Photos Intelligence team
- Implemented dynamic machine learning model that classifies celebrations across different cultures from photos and highlights them through the memory infrastructure
- Scaled infrastructure, server load balancing use-cases, as well as improved performance of high computation processes
- Performed additional exploratory data analysis to make informed technical decisions

#### Software Engineer, Blackstone

*June 2018 - December 2018* 

- Enhanced interface that calculates investment fund scenarios dynamically
- Utilized distributed ledgers and tree data structures to calculate management fees, report growth over time, and evaluate hypotheticals
- Implemented and deployed production features for 300 fund managers

## Teaching Assistant for Programming Languages, Stony Brook University

*January 2018 - May 2018* 

- Hosted biweekly office hours to assist students with assignments written in Python, SML, and Prolog
- Graded assignments and exams for 200 students and detected cheating with plagiarism algorithms

### Coach, Major League Hacking

January 2018 - May 2018

- Liaised with hackathon organizers at 6 universities across the country, ensuring smooth event operation for 2,000 participants
- On-boarded developers with corporate partners' hardware/software and presented opening keynote speeches to start events
- Maintained first responder responsibilities in the case of medical or logistical emergency

### Software Engineering Intern, Softheon

May 2017 - April 2018

- Created reporting web interface used by external clients
- Used sequential patterning to identify recurrences in medical diagnoses
- Documented the on-boarding process used to this day for new hires

### Front End Web Developer, RSRCHR

January 2017 - May 2017

- Contributed towards research interface that allows for cloud supported intensive data processing
- Collaborated with other team members and stakeholders

# Team Leader, Google Ignite CS

March 2016 - June 2017

- Led a team of students in an initiative to make computer science available to 340 students from ages 5-16
- Instructed public school students on computer science topics ranging from 3D modeling, networking, and how to make interactive app

#### **HONORS AND AWARDS**

Google Grace Hopper Conference Grant Recipient, Campus Ambassador to Harvard's WeCode Conference (from 2014-2017), Forbes 30 Under 30 Scholar, Zonta Scholarship Recipient, New York State STEM Incentive Tuition Scholarship

### **PROJECTS**

- Impressionist Photo Filters Image processing experiment which took photos as an input, clustered key colors, segmented by color cluster, computed the convex hull, and rendered brush strokes to create a painting. Then trained a GAN on paintings by Monet and compared the results of the two filters
- Artificial Intelligence Final Project Semester-long exploratory data analysis project investigating gun violence incidents and correlating events to census data and federal and state funding. Utilized clustering, neural networks and explored application of techniques such as Kaplan–Meier estimators
- **Buddy** iOS augmented reality project combined with an emotional digital assistant with the purpose of making the user feel like someone is always supporting them

#### **SKILLS**

 Objective-C/Swift, Python pandas, sklearn, C#/.NET, mySQL, Javascript Node.js, D3, Java, Firebase, Angular/Typescript, C++